
<?xml-model href="../out/schema.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>HI THIS ISN'T DONE :D</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>

         <p>VOGUE</p>
         <p>CHRISTMAS</p>

         <p>WHAT SHE WEARS</p>
         <p>GIFTS-THE BALL GOWNS OF 1896</p>
         <p> On brisk and gay the autumn has been with weddings, two of which were emphatically
            red-letter functions. Then followed the Horse Show, always a dashing affair-a gathering
            of smart men and women, fine horses and equipages, and showy parade of beauty and <rs type="garment">gowns</rs>,
            boxed off and ticketed for the gazing multitudes in genuine peep-show fashion. Men were
            in their best form, and came in for their innings fairly. Gallantry, grooming and good
            looks told with capital effect in the brilliant picture. Now comes the finish of our
            yearly race, with Christmas shopping on the tapis. We are all engaged at this moment in
            thinking much more about the presents we have to make, either from obligation or
            affection, than of what we are having made to wear, or planning to order in the near
            future, or wearing at the present moment. </p>
         <p>The world will bear witness that we are in our apparel as smart as possible; our street
            <rs type="garment">gowns</rs>, <rs type="garment">hats</rs>, <rs type="material">furs</rs> and the rest as faultless and as fit as it is possible to have them.
            The only visible neglect is that we are quite late-and we always are in preparing for
            our toilettes de cérémonie. We shall have to do all that in a rush, as January is only
            three weeks off. But, apropos of the shopping and the gifts, whisper it not in Gath that
            books, pictures, silver, glass, china, etc., are to play a decided second fiddle, this
            year, to <rs type="material">jewels</rs>, <rs type="material">laces</rs> and <rs type="material">furs</rs>, particularly the last of the trio. All my cousins and
            my aunts are talking <rs type="material">fur</rs>, <rs type="material">fur</rs>, <rs type="material">fur</rs>. What wonder, when the creations are so lovely! A
            Christmas list reads off like a menagerie inventory. You will find <rs type="material">seal</rs>, <rs type="material">otter</rs>, <rs type="material">monkey</rs>,
            <rs type="material">beaver</rs> and <rs type="material">bear</rs>; <rs type="material">ermine</rs>, <rs type="material">chinchilla</rs>, <rs type="material">mink</rs>, the <rs type="material">lambs</rs> of Persia and Thibet, <rs type="material">fox</rs> and <rs type="material">lynx</rs>.
            By the way, there is a new departure in making up <rs type="material">lynx</rs> and <rs type="material">fox</rs> in their natural
            skins.</p>
         <p> <rs type="material">Lynx</rs> abounds in lovely coloring, the <note type="color">yellows</note> paling into <note type="color">white</note>, and the long hairs
            flecked with many shades of <note type="color">gray</note>. Thibet is dyed every color, to match different <rs type="material">cloths</rs>,
            and <note type="material">astrachan</note> has gone a peg higher in exclusiveness than its once proud rival, <note type="material"><placeName>Persian</placeName>
            lamb</note>, because the latter is now so well imitated by the manufacturers. The medley of
            <rs type="material">furs</rs> now considered the chic thing has brought about a pooling of <rs type="material">furs</rs> in families, by
            which elder daughters profit, and younger ones are better satisfied with newer purchases
            at less value. De gustibus non. </p>

         <p> Now for un petit mot about ball and <rs type="garment">dinner gowns</rs>, for the dinner-dance season is
            staring us in the face. We all know the succés of <rs type="material">flowers</rs> and <rs type="material">tulle</rs> last year, and we
            are glad to learn that both are to reign in ninety-six. All kinds of <rs type="material">nets</rs>, <rs type="material">gauzes</rs>,
            lisses, and the newest and sheerest of <rs type="material" >grenadines</rs>, flowered like watercolored pictures.
            I hope the débutantes at the coming Patriarchs will scorn <rs type="material">silks</rs> and <rs type="material">satins</rs> for their
            gowns and pay tribute to their own youth and beauty in <rs type="material">tulle</rs>, the ideal <rs type="garment">frock</rs> for that</p>

         <p> Now for un petit mot about ball and dinner gowns, for the dinner-dance season is
            staring us in the face. We all know the succés of flowers and tulle last year, and we
            are glad to learn that both are to reign in ninety-six. All kinds of nets, gauzes,
            lisses, and the newest and sheerest of grenadines, flowered like watercolored pictures.
            I hope the débutantes at the coming Patriarchs will scorn silks and satins for their
            gowns and pay tribute to their own youth and beauty in <note type="i">tulle</note>, the ideal frock for that
            enchanting occasion.</p>
         <p> The rosebud element will monopolize the strictly floral <rs type="garment">gowns</rs> they are theirs by
            natural right, but all young women, matrons or maids, it is to be hoped, will array
            themselves in them for the beauty and becomingness of this poetic fashion. </p>
         <p>As an example of devotion to a <rs type="garment-piece">flower</rs>, the <rs type="garment">gown</rs> in question is trimmed with <rs type="material">myosotis</rs> or
            <rs type="material">forget-me-nots</rs>. There are two immensely full <rs type="garment-piece">skirts</rs> of <rs type="color">white</rs> <rs type="material">tulle</rs> falling over a <rs type="garment-piece">gupe</rs>
            of white soie de Lyons, and all three skirts are gathered on one band. The <rs type="material">tulle</rs> <rs type="garment-piece">skirts</rs>
            are hemmed, with a <rs type="garment-piece">vine heading</rs> embroidered in <rs type="color">white</rs> <rs type="material">floss</rs>, exceedingly dainty and
            effective. The <rs type="garment-piece">collet</rs> <rs type="garment-piece">corsage</rs>, draped in <rs type="material">double tulle</rs>, rises into a slight
            point, back and front, and is headed by a full <rs type="garment-piece">garland</rs> of <rs type="material">forget-me-nots</rs>, which form
            <rs type="garment-piece">shoulder straps</rs> to the <rs type="garment-piece">bodice</rs>. The <rs type="garment-piece">sleeves</rs> are made of many thicknesses of <rs type="material">tulle</rs> caught
            under the flowers on the <rs type="garment-piece">shoulders</rs> and draped so as to expose the arm in front, and then
            draped fully into the armhole in a bouffant way. The <rs type="garment-piece">sleeve</rs> is finished at the elbow by
            a band of a <rs type="color">sky-blue</rs> <rs type="material">velvet</rs>, matching the <rs type="garment-piece">bouquets</rs> which are coquettishly fastened on
            the outside. <rs type="garment-piece">garland of myosotis</rs> is worn round the throat, and connected from this
            <rs type="garment-piece">gorgette</rs> to the <rs type="garment-piece">décolletage</rs> are <rs type="garment-piece">eight floral chains</rs>, slender and lovely; three in the
            back, three in the front, and short ones on each shoulder, which fit over the neck
            perfectly. The <rs type="garment-piece">girdle</rs> is of <rs type="color">sky-blue</rs> <rs type="material">velvet</rs>, fastened in the <rs type="garment-piece">back</rs> with a smart <rs type="garment-piece">bow</rs>.
            <rs type="color">white</rs> <rs type="garment">aigrette</rs>, supported by <rs type="garment-piece">a knot</rs> of forget- me-nots, is posed a little to one side of
            the head, the hair being dressed in waves, rolled off from the face, and pretty,
            careless coils in the back running up into a little knot, with a drooping wave curled in
            the middle of the forehead.</p>
         <p> Another charming gown has floral effects derived from exquisite <rs type="material">silk</rs> <rs type="garment-piece">embroideries</rs>, the
            newest of the fine trimmings. A <rs type="material">satin</rs> <rs type="material">skirt</rs> is the foundation usually for these
            <rs type="garment-piece">transparent draperies</rs> of <rs type="material">tulle</rs> or <rs type="material">gauzes</rs> favored by matrons young and beautiful. </p>
         <p>The skirt, in this instance, is <note type="color">cream-white</note> satin, and the tulle overdress a
            <note type="color">pinkish-mauve</note>, but instead of being hemmed is only doubled, then gathered at the waist,
            and afterward shirred a little distance, say nine or ten inches below, and drawn down
            snugly to the figure and tacked to the <note type="material">satin</note> gupe. Two broad bands of <note type="material">silk</note> embroidery,
            roses in every shade, start en tablier at the bottom of the <note type="material">tulle</note> <rs type="garment">skirt</rs> and are
            graduated a little toward the <rs type="garment-piece">waist</rs>, leaving space for a pointed <rs type="garment">girdle</rs> of the same
            embroidery to show between and encircle the <rs type="garment-piece">waist</rs> in a narrow <rs type="garment">belt</rs>, fastening on the
            left panel with a <rs type="garment">bouquet</rs> of <rs type="material">violets</rs>. <rs type="garment-piece">Corsage bébé</rs>, <rs type="garment-piece">V-shaped décolletage</rs>, headed by a
            broad <rs type="garment-piece">band</rs> of this lovely lisse embroidery, with bouquet of violets on the left
            shoulder. <rs type="color">White</rs> satin <rs type="garment-piece">elbow sleeves</rs> draped with <rs type="material">tulle</rs> so as to show the inner side of
            the arm, across which are two <rs type="garment-piece">narrow straps</rs> of <rs type="material">embroidery</rs>. Hair dressed low on the face,
            a few short curls in the back, and run through the top a superb <rs type="garment">jeweled hairpin</rs>, a
            triple <rs type="material">diamond</rs> <rs type="garment">aigrette</rs>. The <rs type="garment">necklace</rs> is an almost invisible gold chain, from which is
            suspended three enormous <rs type="material">jewels</rs>, a <rs type="material">diamond</rs> in the centre, with <rs type="material">ruby</rs> and <rs type="material">emerald</rs> on
            sides.</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
