<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="../out/schema.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>What She Wears</title>
            <author>Molly Wright</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Vogue Magazine. Transcribed and encoded by Molly Wright.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Transcribed from a 1905 Vogue editorial.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <div type="page" n="1">
            <head>WHAT SHE WEARS.</head>
            <p> BEAUTIFUL BE-FEATHERED OPERA MATINEE <rs type="garment">HATS</rs> - ONLY BOX
               OCCUPANTS MAY DISPLAY THEIR <rs type="garment">HATS</rs> DURING PERFORMANCE - NATTIER
               MODEL COMMENDED <rs type="garment">COSTUMES</rs> FOR CALLING AN ESPECIALLY PRETTY
               SHORT <rs type="garment">SKIRT</rs> MODEL — <rs type="color">BRONZE</rs> AND <rs
                  type="color">OLIVE GREEN</rs>S POPULAR- UNDEFINED <rs type="material"
                  >PLAIDSFEATHER</rs> ARRANGEMENTS </p>
            <p>An opera matinee is sure at all times to bring out the street fashions in strong
               force. Particularly true is it at the November opening, and this year it has proved a
               brilliant example. The beplumed <rs type="garment">hats</rs> assisted with telling
               effects. It is one thing to pass on the street these showy long <rs
                  type="garment-piece">plumes</rs> in <rs type="color">white</rs>, in <rs
                  type="color">blue</rs>, in <rs type="color">pink</rs> and <rs type="color"
                  >yellows</rs>, and quite another to sit from two to three hours gazing at them
               from time to time. <rs type="material">Feathers</rs> in tips seem to have almost
               disappeared. In half lengths they are now disposed at most audacious angles, and
               bunched up into threes or fives. They plunge out from the left side of <rs
                  type="material">velvet</rs>
               <rs type="garment">hats</rs> with <rs type="garment-piece">upturned brims</rs> in a
               rearward direction that is most original. They rise from uptilted and very much
               trimmed backs of <rs type="garment">hats</rs> in stunning bravado. They cross the <rs
                  type="garment-piece">crowns</rs> of smart <rs type="garment">hats</rs> from one
               side almost to the other, and over, and sweep quite far forward upon others. As for
               the <rs type="garment-piece">under brim</rs>
               <rs type="material">feather</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">linings</rs>, as well as the tosssed up <rs
                  type="garment-piece">crown groupings</rs> turning this way and that, they all
               bespeak a skill for posing, and a control over the <rs type="material">feather</rs>
               that never has been as complete as it is this season. The pity of it all was to see
               these exquisite perishable creations taken off and held on the laps. The box
               contingent is in that respect to be envied for keeping the hat on the head.</p>
            <p><note type="image">[An illustration of a woman in ornate dress wearing a great,
                  feathered hat.]</note></p>
            <p><rs type="garment">BOX HAT</rs> IN <rs type="color">PINK</rs></p>
            <p> The charming Nattier styles, and the very low crowned Watteaux should become a fixed
               opera and <rs type="garment">theatre hat</rs>, so easy are they to take off and put
               on, and of the least trouble to keep on one's lap, for <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >plumes</rs> and <rs type="material">feather</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">trimmings</rs> rightfully belong to those in seats where
               hats may be worn on the head throughout the performance. Beautiful were many of the
                  <rs type="garment">box hats</rs>. For instance, one in <rs type="color">pink</rs>
               <rs type="material">velvet</rs>, with a side tilt that seemed every moment to be
               losing its balance, had its <rs type="garment-piece">brim</rs> lined with <rs
                  type="color">pink</rs>
               <rs type="material">tinsel cloth</rs> covered with <rs type="color">pink</rs>
               <rs type="material">tulle</rs>. Five half length <rs type="color">pink</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">plumes</rs> toppled over its <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >crown</rs> and hid it completely. The <rs type="garment-piece">brim</rs> in the
               rear of the <rs type="garment-piece">crown</rs> was also invisible, but in front
               there was a glimpse of it bent down upon the hair and on the right side. The shape of
               the head as well as the dressing of the hair counts for everything in hat styles of
               this character. Another irresistible fascinator was in <rs type="color">white</rs>
               <rs type="material">felt</rs>, and had its <rs type="garment-piece">crown</rs>, which
               was rather high and covered with a fold drapery of <rs type="color"
                  >straw-colored</rs>
               <rs type="material">chiffon velvet</rs> further ornamented on the extreme edge in the
               back with a long and compact bunch of <rs type="color">silvery white</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">aigrettes</rs> spreading backward with a dash. The right
               side edge of the <rs type="garment-piece">brim</rs> of this hat almost touched the
               beauty's eyebrow, while on the left, the uptilt showed off the whole head. At the
               same marvellous angle was posed a <rs type="color">white silver </rs>
               <rs type="material">cloth</rs> creation, showing its sheen only upon the <rs
                  type="garment-piece">brim</rs>. The <rs type="garment-piece">crown</rs> was
               extremely large, having a wrinkled <rs type="garment-piece">drapery</rs> of <rs
                  type="color">pale blue</rs>
               <rs type="material">velvet</rs> very full and gracefully disposed. In the most
               picturesque manner were <placeName>France</placeName>
               <rs type="material">roses</rs> in their dainty <rs type="color">pinkness</rs>,
               grouped into a <rs type="garment-piece">garland</rs> on the left, a few <rs
                  type="material">roses</rs> swinging below the <rs type="garment-piece">brim
                  line</rs> on that side which was abridged for that particular effect evidently.
               For pure coquetry no hat has ever excelled it. </p>
            <p><note type="image">[An illustration depicting a man in fancy dress, wearing a large
                  coat and top hat wearing a cane. In front of him is a fancily dressed woman
                  wearing a dress with puffy sleeves and a hat with feathers and a sort of
                  veil.]</note></p>
            <p>NEW <rs type="garment">COIFFURE</rs></p>
            <p> One <rs type="garment">coiffure</rs> there was that stood out from all the rest on a
               recent night performance. It consisted of two large <rs type="color">scarlet</rs> and
                  <rs type="color">white</rs>
               <rs type="material">velvet tiger lilies</rs> grouped with two or three <rs
                  type="color">dull green</rs>
               <rs type="material">velvet leaves</rs>, and a <rs type="garment-piece">Paradise
                  plume</rs> of <rs type="color">silvery whiteness</rs> springing from the midst.
               This <rs type="garment">coiffure</rs> was posed slightly out of the middle line on
               the back of the head (the hair being dressed high), but leaning a trifle toward the
               left side. A copy it is said to be of a <rs type="garment">coiffure</rs> worn at the
               popular <placeName>French</placeName> play called La Belle Madame Héber. It marks a
               new departure, taking the place of a <rs type="garment">theatre hat</rs>. </p>
            <p>There seems to be no chance, however, this season to oust the famous large <rs
                  type="garment">picture hats</rs>, or the smaller styles just described. What may
               happen in the autumn of 1906 remains to be seen.</p>
            <p><note type="image">[An illustration of two women in fancy dress. One stands, holding
                  a dark purse. The other sits over a tea set. </note></p>
            <p>SMART THINGS HIGH-PRICED</p>
            <p> If ever there was a time when so-called poor relations might joyfully accept
               presents of things wearable, it is undoubtedly this year. The advance in prices for
               really smart <rs type="garment">hats</rs>, <rs type="garment">costumes</rs>, <rs
                  type="garment">evening wraps</rs>, <rs type="garment">sets</rs> of <rs
                  type="material">furs</rs>, or of <rs type="material">ostrich</rs> and <rs
                  type="material">marabou</rs> puts the small-income sisters, aunts and cousins of
               the rich in quite a trying situation. No small economies can overcome the rise to the
               fabulous sums that are asked at the smart places. </p>
            <p>HALF TAILORED <rs type="garment">STREET COSTUMES</rs></p>
            <p>
               <rs type="garment">Street costumes</rs> for forenoon wear are worn short, and will
               be. But there are <rs type="garment">cloth costumes</rs> only half-tailored, which
               are quite elaborate, and expensively trimmed, the skirts of which are long. These
               are, of course, specially intended to pay visits in, or to wear upon any ceremonious
               occasion. Ladies' or <rs type="garment">chiffon cloths</rs> in single colors are for
               these, the best style. The length of the <rs type="garment">skirt</rs> indicates that
               the wearer, if she walks, must take it up. Hansom and cab-hire has become so general
               nowadays that few will be inclined to go through the weariness of carrying their <rs
                  type="garment">skirts</rs> in the grasp of the hand. Many dressy <rs
                  type="material">cloths</rs> and <rs type="material">velveteens</rs> in <rs
                  type="garment-piece">short-skirted</rs>
               <rs type="garment">costumes</rs> mark the independence of those who are to make their
               calls afoot in the season. </p>
            <p>A <rs type="garment">SHORT SKIRT</rs> MODEL</p>
            <p> When a choice has to be made among the short-skirted tailor-mades the many models
               shown are so charming that it becomes a difficult matter to order. There are complex
               designs that appear quite simple in the sober colors, but are very ornate in <rs
                  type="material">cloths</rs> of lighter shades. A long <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >tab</rs> design, cut in one piece with the <rs type="garment-piece">yoke</rs> or
               with the <rs type="garment-piece">Princess girdle top</rs> , is extremely graceful,
               as <rs type="garment-piece">full plaits</rs> are set in to suit the figure or
               lessened as the demand arises. <rs type="garment-piece">Braids</rs> to match the
               cloth or glossy <rs type="color">black</rs>
               <rs type="material">silk</rs> ones in some way or another enter into the bottom <rs
                  type="garment">skirt trimming</rs>. It is kept in most cases quite low on the
               bottom, and not at all conspicuous, the main object being not to detract from the
               length of <rs type="garment-piece">skirt line</rs>. Passementerie motives are
               introduced with soutaches, while wider braids produce of themselves sufficient
               effect. </p>
            <p><rs type="garment">BODICE</rs> TREATMENT</p>
            <p> The close-fitting <rs type="garment">bodices</rs> receive color bits upon their
               revers, mostly very small ones, or have flat shapes in color laid on about the neck,
               lower down upon the <rs type="garment-piece">belt</rs>, and both in front and in the
               back, as well as upon the bottom of the <rs type="garment-piece">sleeves</rs>. Buckle
               ornaments are put in pairs upon the <rs type="garment">belts</rs> or as an ornament
               on the top of <rs type="garment-piece">princess girdles</rs> both back and front.
               This finish is a very smart one. All the <rs type="garment">bodices</rs> keep up
               either Eton or <rs type="material">bolèro</rs> suggestions. A few exceptions adopt
               the <rs type="garment-piece">basque line</rs> or the <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >postilion</rs>, but these are not found among the younger slim figures. <rs
                  type="garment-piece">Shoulders</rs> are, or should be, kept on broad lines; there
               is no style without that feature in tailor-mades. Some <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >sleeves</rs> have less fulness than others at the top. Both long and elbow <rs
                  type="garment-piece">sleeve</rs> lengths are worn. </p>
            <p><note type="image">[An illustration of a woman in profile, wearing the same sort of
                  hat as described. Behind her is a table with a lamp. </note></p>
         </div>
         <div type="page" n="2">
            <p><note type="image">[An illustration depicting flowers and two doves nesting on top.]</note></p>
            <p> Among some extremely late coming tailor models long sleeves prevail, <rs
                  type="material">Lace</rs>
               <rs type="garment">chemisettes</rs> give rise to openings at the neck that are
               exceedingly becoming, and stands for no end of smartness in these costumes. </p>
            <p><rs type="color">BRONZE</rs> AND <rs type="color">OLIVE GREEN</rs></p>
            <p> As the season advances <rs type="color">bronze</rs> and <rs type="color">olive
                  green</rs>s increase in color distinction among the <rs type="material"
                  >cloths</rs> and <rs type="material">velvets</rs>. An example in <rs type="color"
                  >olive green</rs> in the finest of <rs type="material">cloth</rs>, had for
               trimming, an inch and a half <rs type="color">black</rs>
               <rs type="material">brocade</rs>
               <rs type="material">galoon</rs>. It was a <rs type="garment">two-piece suit</rs>, a
               closed Eton and skirt. This galoon from <rs type="garment-piece">shoulders</rs> to
                  <rs type="garment-piece">hem</rs> in front gave long lines in even rows, the <rs
                  type="material">cloth</rs> between being cut into a flat flap, which raised itself
               sufficiently to keep the width of the <rs type="material">galoon</rs> intact In the
               back these long lines were pre-served, giving a tapering effect to the <rs
                  type="garment-piece">waist</rs> which was belted in with cloth to match, but also
               had shaped oblong applications of light <rs type="color">grayish-blue</rs>
               <rs type="material">velvet</rs>, over which were motives of <rs type="color"
                  >black</rs>
               <rs type="material">silk</rs>
               <rs type="material">passementerie</rs>. A turn-over <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >collar</rs>, now the accepted finish of all the best tailor-mades, and in this
               instance it was not wanting. It was also of <rs type="color">blue</rs>
               <rs type="material">velvet</rs>, over-applied with <rs type="color">black</rs>
               <rs type="material">passementerie</rs>. The bottom of the sleeves repeated the same
               ornamentation, while upon the fronts of the Eton, on the <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >bust line</rs>, were two <rs type="color">black</rs> pieces similarly treated.
               Charming indeed was this <rs type="garment-piece">trimming</rs> effect, while the <rs
                  type="material">galoon</rs> in its glossy flatness seemed to be woven into the <rs
                  type="material">cloth</rs>, so admirably was it sewed and pressed. </p>
            <p><note type="image">[An illustration of a woman in profile with an updo.]</note></p>
            <p><rs type="color">TOBACCO-BROWN</rs> COSTUME</p>
            <p> Of the utmost attractiveness was a <rs type="color">tobacco-brown</rs>
               <rs type="material">cloth</rs> costume, short skirted, as well, with a low crutch
               design separating the <rs type="garment-piece">plaits</rs>, and in the same brown
               shade as the cloth. On one edge of this <rs type="color">brown</rs>
               <rs type="material">silk</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">Hercules braid</rs> was a narrow raised <rs type="color"
                  >brown</rs>
               <rs type="material">satin</rs>
               <rs type="material">cord</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">gimp</rs>, which, when sewed on, gave a special accent to
               the long <rs type="garment-piece">crutch lines</rs> that ran up from the bottom, and
               were lost in their diminutive ending. A <rs type="garment-piece">panel</rs> front had
               the <rs type="material">cloth</rs> cut into graded crescent lengths from top to
               bottom, a darker shade of <rs type="color">brown</rs>
               <rs type="material">silk</rs> showing underneath. Crescent was finished by the
               narrowest <rs type="material">cord</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">inlet</rs> and stitched to flatness. </p>
            <p>The same <rs type="garment-piece">trimming</rs> displayed itself upon the sides of
               the sleeves from shoulder to cuff, and gave a <rs type="garment-piece">yoke</rs> line
               back and front, in three graded rows beautifully proportioned in their size. A touch
               of <rs type="color">gold</rs>
               <rs type="material">galoon</rs> brightened up the turn-over <rs type="color"
                  >brown</rs>
               <rs type="material">velvet</rs> collar, as it did the straight <rs
                  type="garment-piece">cuff</rs> pieces; while a glimpse of both <rs type="material"
                  >velvet</rs> and <rs type="color">gold</rs> suggested an inner <rs type="garment"
                  >vest</rs> line in perfect harmony. All the fastenings in front were quite
               invisible. </p>
            <p> INDEFINITE <rs type="color">PLAIDS</rs>
            </p>
            <p>Those almost undefined <rs type="color">plaid</rs> cloths in <rs type="color"
                  >greens</rs> or <rs type="color">bronze</rs> with <rs type="color">red</rs>dish
               and <rs type="color">dark blue</rs>ish <rs type="garment-piece">shad-braids</rs> of
                  <rs type="material">silk</rs>en <rs type="color">black</rs>ness are twisted into a
               telling design upon each side of this straight band. A Norfolk style of short
               belted-in <rs type="garment">coat</rs>, with a <rs type="color">red</rs>
               <rs type="material">cloth</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">collar</rs> and <rs type="garment-piece">cuffs</rs>, the <rs
                  type="color">black</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">braid</rs> again used as <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >trimming</rs> and a few <rs type="garment-piece">gilt buttons</rs> laid upon the
                  <rs type="garment">belt</rs> and the fronts produce a markedly good and out-of-
               the-common style.</p>
            <p><note type="image">[An illustration of a woman in a dark dress and large hat. In the background, the shadow of what appears to be a man in a horse-drawn carriage.]</note></p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
