<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<<<<<<< HEAD
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<?xml-model href="../out/schema.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
=======
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
>>>>>>> 8e9614db0014b286ebbad4029eab43d497d68257
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Debutante</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>156</p>
         <p>Frances Mclaughlein</p>
        
         <p>Debututante </p>

         <p> 
            Many happy returns to the Debutante Party 
            (even without the old fine “careless rapture”). There is hardly one Debutante who does not
<<<<<<< HEAD
            include, in her daily schedule, work for some of the great relief needs, college
            course, Nurse Aid or Day Nursery work. But over this layer of serious ideas and genuine
            good works there is again this year the light but delicious frosting of debutante
            parties. Most of them will again be the great group presentation balls which were wartime
            innovations but there will be a few individual parties. The debutante this year may
            still not have a seven man escort as her mother might have had ; she will quite probably
            rush down for college for her own debut; there will be fewer fittings, fewer debutante
            luncheons, much, much less flurry. And although clothes may seem less important to her
            than to her pre-war debutante predecessors , she will probably manage to affix her
            personal signature to her own wardrobe; will know that it is not “ how many” but “how
            memorable” that really matters, when she chooses her clothes. With her beautiful <rs type="color">white</rs>
            Coming Out <rs type="garment">party dress</rs> this season a debutante may wear a short <rs type="color">crimson</rs> <rs type="material">velvet</rs> or
            <rs type="material">duvetyne</rs> <rs type="garment">coat</rs>. Wear <rs type="garment">wrist-length gloves</rs> in <rs type="color">white</rs> , and carry a tight little white furs
            (opposite page). If it is not her coming out party,she will probably choose a
            colour. When it is not a party, but just a small dancing evening dress again, this season
            … <rs type="color">black</rs> perhaps...bare on top as her debut dress.
            
            <note type="image"> Image </note>
            
            WHITE TO COME OUT IN.
          
            Beautiful, <rs type="garment-piece">great-skirted </rs> <rs type="garment">ball dress</rs> made for Miss Betty Tyson by Herman Patrick tappe of heavy
=======
            include,in her daily schedule, work for some of the great relief needs, college
            course,Nurse Aid or Day Nursery work.But over this layer of serious ideas and genuine
            good works there is again this year the light but delicious frosting of debutante
            parties.Most of them will again be the great group presentation balls which were wartime
            innovations but there will be a few individual parties. The debutante this year may
            still not have a seven man escort as her mother might have had ; she will quite probably
            rush down for college for her own debut; there will be fewer fittings, fewer debutante
            luncheons, much,much less <note type="material">flurry.</note> And although clothes may seem less important to her
            than to her pre-war debutante predecessors , she will probably manage to affix her
            personal signature to her own wardrobe; will know that it is not “ how many” but “how
            memorable” that really matters, when she chooses her clothes. With her beautiful white
            Coming Out party dress this season a debutante may wear a<note type="clothes"> short crimson velvet</note> or
            duvetyn coat. Wear <note type="accessory">wrist- length white gloves</note> , and carry a tight little white furs
            (opposite page). If it is not her coming out party,she will probably choose a
            colour.When it is not a party,but just a small dancing evening dress again, this season
            … black perhaps...bare on top as her debut dress.
            
            <note type="photo"> Image </note>
            
            WHITE TO COME OUT IN.
          
            Beautiful, great-skirted ball dress made for Miss Betty Tyson by Herman Patrick tappe of heavy
>>>>>>> 8e9614db0014b286ebbad4029eab43d497d68257
            silk brocade, plumed and embroidered with medallions of sequins, rhinestones,bugle
            beads. Miss Tyson daughter of Mr.and Mrs George Tyson made her debut in November at a
            party given by her aunt,Mrs.Geogre Mesta,in Washington. </p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
