<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" 
type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<?xml-model href="../hwODD.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Pretty Color; Easy Fashion</title>
            <author>Trinity Taylor</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Vogue Magazine. Transcribed and encoded by Trinity Taylor.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Transcribed from a 1975 Vogue editorial, photographed by Avedon and published by
               Condé Nast.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>

   <text>
      <body>

         <div type="page" n="1">
            <p>Pretty color; easy fashion</p>
            <p>TOGETHER AGAIN!</p>
            <p>News at night, right—the look of a top and, instead of pants, a long slim skirt—this
               season’s newest “pijama dressing!” Here’s Geoffrey Beene’s super-soft,
               north-of-south-version—blue-eyed, gray-pink plaid <note type="material">silk
                  crepe</note>. Geoffrey designed the shirt-and-sash-side and one of his new
               T-shirt-based tops. And a beautiful way it unwraps—beautifully. Gianfranco Ferré,
               about $950. At Lord &amp; Taylor, N.Y.; Gattle’s, Bal Harbour; Magnin; Liberty House,
               Hawaii. Accessories and men’s fashion details, next to last page. These 12 pages:
               hair, Harry King of Cinandre; makeup, Way Bandy.</p>

            <p>The kind of dress a lot of women have been beating the bushes for years, left—a
               short, simply pretty late-day/little-dinner dress—banana <note type="material">silk
                  crepe de Chine</note>, bare-necked, with sleeves that just slip off the shoulder.
               Monty Susman for Mollie Parnis; Altair, Coondogale Silk Company. About $385. Bergdorf
               Goodman; Saks; Neiman-Marcus; Lillie Rubin—South and West; Swanson’s. A reminder:
               those woodsy, misty scents for men (Aramis for one) are a nice mood-changer at night.
               And who knows, maybe your scents won’t clash.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Models in gray-pink plaid dress and yellow wrap dress, leaning and
                  walking on stairs. Series of smaller frames showing playful stairway
                  scenes.</note></p>
            <p>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

         <div type="page" n="2">
            <p>Part of the fashion idiom: “easy dressing”—meaning dressing that’s unstudied,
               uncomplicated, easy to wear… all in an attractive, polished, real-life way. The
               concept’s American. We started it. We do it best. And we keep doing it better. This
               season, “easy” goes to a whole new level—racier, sharper, more sophisticated. What
               does it: fabric with more character, patterns with more strength, more precision…
               color!</p>

            <p>There’s a new character to Ralph Lauren’s sportier American classics, like his
               traditional <note type="garment">trousers</note>, this page, are in a bold floral
               print of <note type="material">silk</note>, and his shawl-collared “robe” is vivid
               purple in soft, languorous <note type="material">silk charmeuse</note>. Another plus:
               these looks needn’t wait for warm weather, a resort—this is terrific at-home dressing
               any time. Trousers, about $358. Robe-jacket, about $658. Late Dec. at Saks Fifth
               Avenue, NYC; Hudson-Belk’s, Raleigh NC; Polo/Ralph Lauren, San Antonio. Ring and
               bracelet, Paloma Picasso for Tiffany &amp;amp; Co. Donald Judd chair, courtesy Max Protetch
               Gallery, NYC.</p>

            <p>Everybody loved the look, the Fred Astaire nonchalance of Ralph Lauren’s impeccable,
               classic <note type="garment">trousers</note>… in brilliant chrome <note
                  type="material">silk charmeuse</note>, opposite. Here, played against a navy
               double-breasted <note type="material">wool gabardine</note> jacket and white tank.
               Trousers, about $358. Jacket, about $396. Late December at Barneys New York;
               Polo/Ralph Lauren, Costa Mesa CA; Polo/Ralph Lauren, Denver, Polo/Ralph Lauren, San
               Francisco. Rings and bracelets, Bulgari at the Pierre Hotel, NYC. Elizabeth Jackson
               chair for Arc International, Inc., NYC. These, next two pages: hair, Madeleine Cofano
               for Bruno Dessange; makeup, Laura Mercier. Details, more stores, last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Models in bold floral trousers, purple robe, and yellow scarf;
                  second in bright yellow pants and black jacket with polka-dot scarf.</note></p>
            <p>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

         <div type="page" n="3">
            <p>A STRONG SENSE OF EASE</p>
            <p>Typical of this “laid back” American approach: very polished sweater-and-skirt
               dressing for low-key evenings. And what a sweater-and-skirt this is! By Ralph Lauren,
               this page, a long, soft-moving, bias-cut skirt of flag-red <note type="material">silk
                  crepe de Chine</note> with a generously sized navy cotton turtleneck sweater. The
               turtleneck—so important this winter—keeps evolving for warm weather, with long
               sleeves, short sleeves, even on halters. Skirt, about $258. Sweater, about $198.
               Turnout late December at Allcott &amp;amp; Andrews, NYC; Short Hills NJ; Hartford CT;
               Washington DC; Polo/Ralph Lauren, Atlanta; Polo/Ralph Lauren, Ft. Lauderdale.
               Elizabeth Jackson chair for Arc International, Inc., NYC.</p>

            <p>Pure pow! The dress everybody applauded, wanted!—Donna Karan’s—opposite. In
               double-faced, full-bodied bright red <note type="material">silk</note>—strong
               shouldered, tightly cinched at the waist, with a graceful, ankle-length skirt—it sets
               up a whole new definition of shape and kind of dressing for easy evenings. Donna
               Karan New York. About $890. Late December. At Bloomingdale’s, L.H. Rogers, Salem MA;
               Alexander’s, Virginia Beach; Hudson’s, Hattie; Palm Beach FL and Scottsdale AZ;
               Eleanor Keeshan, Los Angeles. Chair, Lawrence Originals, c. 1960, courtesy Fifty-50,
               NYC. Details, more stores, see last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Models in red silk dress, navy sweater and red skirt, posed on
                  geometric red-and-white chairs.</note></p>
            <p>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

         <div type="page" n="4">
            <p>A STRONG SENSE OF EASE… PATTERNS ARE PRECISE, SHARP—UNSENTIMENTAL</p>
            <p>The best of these patterns, when they aren’t in strong color, are in strong black or
               navy with white, like this very attractive city dressing for working women—easy to
               wear, but polished, meant to be taken seriously. David Hayes’s black-and-white <note
                  type="garment">suit</note>, left: a body-close, pointed-edge jacket and short,
               narrow skirt, both in strongly textured <note type="material">silk cloque</note>—a
               look that moves from day into evening. About $460.</p>

            <p>Regimental precision—the navy-and-white stripes, right—of Gloria Sachs’s <note
                  type="material">silk</note> button-back blouse and classic <note type="garment"
                  >trouser</note>, all the raciness of a jumpsuit. Top, about $220. Trousers, about
               $290. And then there are patterns so precise, they give you a feeling of texture.
               Anne Klein’s starring jacket, left—long, clean, collarless—continues in
               black-and-white, perfect proportion with this short, slim <note type="material"
                  >linen/satin</note> skirt; with trousers. Louis Dell’Olio for Anne Klein &amp; Co.
               Jacket, about $380; skirt, about $160. Jewelry, Paloma Picasso for Tiffany &amp; Co.</p>

            <p>Another attractive jacket, right, by Mondi, in <note type="material">navy
                  gabardine</note>, slightly more classic but not blazer-y—it’s longer, more
               relaxed, it moves. Here, over matching trousers, a white shirt. Jacket, about $209.
               Trousers, about $160. Shirt, about $120. Hair, Edward Tricomi for Pipino-Buccheri,
               NYC; makeup, Laura Mercier. Details, more stores, see last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Models in patterned black-and-white and navy outfits, posed in
                  studio and seated near luxury car.</note></p>
            <p>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

         <div type="page" n="5">
            <p>A STRONG SENSE OF EASE… THE SINGULAR CHARM OF A SOFT SUIT IN A STRONG MIX OF
               PATTERNS</p>
            <p>Usually hard to find: suit dressing that strikes the right balance between crispness
               and ease. You find it, opposite, in Oscar de la Renta’s striking plaid/check <note
                  type="garment">suit</note> of navy-and-white <note type="material">wool</note>—the
               jacket lightly shaped and rounded; the skirt short, narrow, slit; the look sharpened
               by the jolt of a red-and-white striped <note type="material">silk</note> blouse.
               About $1190. Late January at Saks Fifth Avenue; Sara Fredericks, Boston &amp; Palm Beach;
               Montaldo’s; Higbee’s; Balle’s. Jean Prouvé chair, Global Furniture, NYC.</p>

            <p>In a more dressed mood, this page, Bill Blass’s soft-falling 7/8 coat and slim skirt,
               in a deep, knee-length shaft of gray <note type="material">silk</note>, in a
               controlled, allover “palmette” print (fabric, Abraham) with a striped <note
                  type="garment">silk halter</note> that wraps at the waist (Blass, Telos). Gray at
               night, a pulled-together, charming way to look. About $2570. Late January at Saks
               Fifth Avenue, NYC; Sara Fredericks, Boston; Martha, Palm Beach &amp; Bloomingdale’s, Holt
               Baldwin, St. Petersburg, OH; Frost Bros. Hair, Ray Allington for Vidal Sassoon;
               makeup, Margaret Avery. Details, more stores, last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Models in plaid suit with striped blouse and gray patterned coat,
                  posed leaning against luxury car at night.</note></p>
            <p>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
