<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng"
type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng"
type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Strong Sense of Ease</title>
            <author>Trinity Taylor</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Vogue Magazine. Transcribed and encoded by Trinity Taylor.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Transcribed from a 1985 Vogue editorial, photographed by Andrea Blanch and published
               by Condé Nast.</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>

   <text>
      <body>

         <div type="page" n="1">

            <p>Part of the fashion idiom, “easy dressing”—meaning dressing that’s unstudied,
               uncomplicated, easy to wear… all in an attractive, polished, real-life way. The
               concept’s American. We started it. We do it best. And we keep doing it better. This
               season, “easy” goes to a whole new level—racier, sharper, more sophisticated. What
               does it: fabric with more character, patterns with more strength, more precision…
               color!</p>

            <p>There’s a new character to Ralph Lauren’s sportive American classics, like his
               traditional <rs type="garment">trousers</rs>, this page, are in a bold floral print
               of <rs type="material">silk</rs>, and his <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >shawl-collared</rs>
               <rs type="garment">robe</rs> is vivid <rs type="color">purple</rs> in soft,
               languorous <rs type="material">silk charmeuse</rs>. Another plus: these looks needn’t
               wait for warm weather, a resort—this is terrific at-home dressing any time. <rs
                  type="garment">Trousers</rs>, about $358. <rs type="garment">Robe-jacket</rs>,
               about $658. Late Dec. at Saks Fifth Avenue, NYC; Hudson-Belk’s, Raleigh NC;
               Polo/Ralph Lauren, San Antonio. Ring and bracelet, Paloma Picasso for Tiffany &amp;
               Co. Donald Judd chair, courtesy Max Protetch Gallery, NYC.</p>

            <p>Everybody loved the look, the Fred Astaire nonchalance of Ralph Lauren’s impeccable,
               classic <rs type="garment">trousers</rs>, in brilliant chrome <rs type="material"
                  >silk charmeuse</rs>, opposite. Here, played against a <rs type="color">navy</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">double-breasted</rs>
               <rs type="material">wool gabardine</rs>
               <rs type="garment">jacket</rs> and <rs type="color">white</rs>
               <rs type="garment">tank</rs>. <rs type="garment">Trousers</rs>, about $358. <rs
                  type="garment">Jacket</rs>, about $396. Late December at Barneys New York;
               Polo/Ralph Lauren, Costa Mesa CA; Polo/Ralph Lauren, Denver; Polo/Ralph Lauren, San
               Francisco. <rs type="garment">Rings</rs> and <rs type="garment">bracelets</rs>,
               Bulgari at the Pierre Hotel, NYC. Elizabeth Jackson chair for Arc International,
               Inc., NYC. These, next two pages: hair, Madeleine Cofano for Bruno Dessange; makeup,
               Laura Mercier. Details, more stores, last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Image: full-page color spread of Ralph Lauren trousers and
                  robe.</note></p>
            <p>Andrea Blanch<lb/>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>

         </div>

         <div type="page" n="2">

            <p>A STRONG SENSE OF EASE</p>

            <p>Typical of this “laid back” American approach: very polished <rs type="garment"
                  >sweater</rs>-and-<rs type="garment">skirt</rs> dressing for low-key evenings. And
               what a <rs type="garment">sweater</rs>-and-<rs type="garment">skirt</rs> this is! By
               Ralph Lauren, this page, a long, soft-moving, <rs type="garment-piece">bias-cut
                  skirt</rs> of <rs type="color">flag-red</rs>
               <rs type="material">silk crepe de Chine</rs> with a generously sized <rs type="color"
                  >navy</rs>
               <rs type="material">cotton</rs>
               <rs type="garment">turtleneck sweater</rs>. The <rs type="garment">turtleneck</rs>—so
               important this winter—keeps evolving for warm weather, with <rs type="garment-piece"
                  >long sleeves</rs>, <rs type="garment-piece">short sleeves</rs>, even on <rs
                  type="garment-piece">halters</rs>. <rs type="garment">Skirt</rs>, about $258. <rs
                  type="garment">Sweater</rs>, about $198. Turnout late December at Alcott &amp;
               Andrews, NYC; Short Hills NJ; Hartford CT; Washington DC; Polo/Ralph Lauren, Atlanta.
               Skirt, Polo/Ralph Lauren, Ft. Lauderdale. Elizabeth Jackson chair for Arc
               International, Inc., NYC.</p>

            <p>Pure pow! The dress everybody applauded, wanted!—Donna Karan’s—opposite. In
               double-faced, full-bodied <rs type="color">bright red</rs>
               <rs type="material">silk</rs>—strong shouldered, tightly cinched at the <rs
                  type="garment-piece">waist</rs>, with a graceful, ankle-length <rs type="garment"
                  >skirt</rs>—it sets up a whole new definition of shape and a new kind of dressing
               for easy evenings. Donna Karan New York. About $890. Late January. At Bloomingdale’s;
               L.H. Rogers, Salem MA; Alexander’s Edge, Virginia Beach; Hudson’s, Hattie, Palm Beach
               FL and Scottsdale AZ; Eleanor Keehan, Los Angeles. Chair, Lawrence Originals, c.
               1960, courtesy Fifty-50, NYC. Details, more stores, see next to last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Image: model seated in red silk skirt and navy sweater.</note></p>
            <p>Andrea Blanch<lb/>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

         <div type="page" n="3">
            <p><note type="image">Image only page: full-page visual continuation of “A Strong Sense
                  of Ease” — two models in monochrome knits and silk, photographed mid-motion
                  against a neutral backdrop.</note></p>
            <p>Andrea Blanch<lb/>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

         <div type="page" n="4">

            <p>A STRONG SENSE OF EASE… PATTERNS ARE PRECISE, SHARP—UNSENTIMENTAL</p>

            <p>The best of these patterns, when they aren’t in strong color, are in strong <rs
                  type="color">black</rs> or <rs type="color">navy</rs> with <rs type="color"
                  >white</rs>, like this very attractive city dressing for working women—easy to
               wear, but polished, meant to be taken seriously. David Hayes’s <rs type="color"
                  >black</rs>-and-<rs type="color">white</rs>
               <rs type="garment">suit</rs>, left: a body-close, pointed-edge <rs type="garment"
                  >jacket</rs> and short, narrow <rs type="garment">skirt</rs>, both in strongly
               textured <rs type="material">silk cloque</rs>—a look that moves from day into
               evening. About $460.</p>

            <p>Regimental precision—the <rs type="color">navy</rs>-and-<rs type="color">white</rs>
               stripes, right, of Gloria Sachs’s <rs type="material">silk</rs>
               <rs type="garment-piece">button-back</rs>
               <rs type="garment">blouse</rs> and classic <rs type="garment">trouser</rs>: all the
               raciness of a <rs type="garment">jumpsuit</rs>. <rs type="garment">Top</rs>, about
               $220. <rs type="garment">Trousers</rs>, about $290. And then there are patterns so
               precise, they give you a feeling of texture. Anne Klein’s starring <rs type="garment"
                  >jacket</rs>, left—long, clean, collarless—continues in <rs type="color"
                  >black</rs>-and-<rs type="color">white</rs>, perfect proportion with this short,
               slim <rs type="material">linen</rs>/<rs type="material">satin</rs>
               <rs type="garment">skirt</rs>; with <rs type="garment">trousers</rs>. Louis Dell’Olio
               for Anne Klein &amp; Co. <rs type="garment">Jacket</rs>, about $380; <rs
                  type="garment">skirt</rs>, about $160. <rs type="garment">Jewelry</rs>, Paloma
               Picasso for Tiffany &amp; Co.</p>

            <p>Another attractive <rs type="garment">jacket</rs>, right, by Mondi, in <rs
                  type="color">navy</rs><rs type="material"> gabardine</rs>, slightly more classic
               but not <rs type="garment">blazer</rs>-y—it’s longer, more relaxed, it moves. Here,
               over matching <rs type="garment">trousers</rs>, a <rs type="color">white</rs>
               <rs type="garment">shirt</rs>. <rs type="garment">Jacket</rs>, about $209. <rs
                  type="garment">Trousers</rs>, about $160. <rs type="garment">Shirt</rs>, about
               $120. Hair, Edward Tricomi for Pipino-Buccheri, NYC; makeup, Laura Mercier. Details,
               more stores, see last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Image: two standing models, one in a black-and-white Hayes suit,
                  another in navy stripes.</note></p>
            <p>Andrea Blanch<lb/>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>

         </div>

         <div type="page" n="5">
            <p><note type="image">Image only page: editorial photo featuring models seated in
                  tailored jackets and striped blouses, architectural background.</note></p>
            <p>Andrea Blanch<lb/>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

         <div type="page" n="6">

            <p>A STRONG SENSE OF EASE… THE SINGULAR CHARM OF A SOFT SUIT IN A STRONG MIX OF
               PATTERNS</p>

            <p>Usually hard to find: <rs type="garment">suit</rs> dressing that strikes the right
               balance between crispness and ease. You find it, opposite, in Oscar de la Renta’s
               striking plaid/check <rs type="garment">suit</rs> of navy-and-white <rs
                  type="material">wool</rs>—the <rs type="garment">jacket</rs> lightly shaped and
               rounder, the <rs type="garment">skirt</rs> short, narrow, slit; the look sharpened by
               the jolt of a <rs type="color">red</rs>-and-<rs type="color">white</rs> striped <rs
                  type="material">silk</rs>
               <rs type="garment">blouse</rs>. About $1190. Late January at Saks Fifth Avenue; Sara
               Fredericks, Boston &amp; Palm Beach; Montaldo’s; Higbee’s; Balle’s. Jean Prouvé
               chair, Global Furniture, NYC.</p>

            <p>In a more dressed mood, this page, Bill Blass’s soft-falling <rs type="garment">7/8
                  coat</rs> and slim, softly shaped, <rs type="garment">knee-length straight
                  skirt</rs>, in a controlled, allover “palmette” print (fabric, Abraham) with
               stripes: a striped <rs type="material">silk</rs>
               <rs type="garment">halter</rs> that wraps at the throat (Delbos, Teseo), glory at
               night, a pulled-together, altogether charming way to look. About $2570. Late January
               at Saks Fifth Avenue, NYC; Sara Fredericks, Boston; Martha, Palm Beach &amp; Bal
               Harbour; John Baldwin, St. Petersburg FL; Frost Bros., San Antonio and Ohio; Frost
               Bros. Hair, Ray Allington for Vidal Sassoon; makeup, Margaret Avery. Details, more
               stores, last pages.</p>

            <p><note type="image">Image: model in de la Renta check suit and red striped
                  blouse.</note></p>
            <p>Andrea Blanch<lb/>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>

         </div>

         <div type="page" n="7">
            <p><note type="image">Image only page: full-page color photograph closing the series —
                  model in plaid Oscar de la Renta suit, seated beside red-striped fabric
                  backdrop.</note></p>
            <p>Andrea Blanch<lb/>Copyright © 2012 Condé Nast</p>
         </div>

      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
