<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>What She Wears</title>
            <author>Vogue Magezine</author>
            <editor>Tara McGee</editor>
         </titleStmt>

         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Penn State University, Digital Humanities</publisher>
            <date when="2025">2025</date>
            <availability status="free">
               <p>Distributed for educational and research use only.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title level="a">What She Wears</title>
               <author>Vogue Magazine</author>
               <pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
               <publisher>Condé Nast</publisher>
               <date when="1915-12-01">December 1, 1915</date>
               <note>Transcribed from the December 1, 1915 issue of <title level="j">Vogue</title>,
                  Published by Condé Nast in New York.</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>

   <text>
      <body>
         <p>December 1 65</p>
         <p>SEEN in the SHOPS</p>

         <p><note type="garment">Skating Sets</note> to Play Up the Latest Sport, Pretty Boudoir Things for Christmas Gifts, and
            Two Practical Waists for a Balance Wheel</p>
         <p>(illustration of a woman wearing a checkered scarf, hat, and muff.) Since skating bids
            fair to succeed dancing as a fas, a skating set of <note type="material">velveteen</note> and <note type="material">chiffon</note> <note type="material">velvet</note> is one
            of the most acceptable fights; <note type="garment">hat</note>, $10; <note type="garment">scarf</note>, $15; <note type="garment">muff</note>, $40</p>
         <p>(illustration of a woman wearing <note type="color">white</note> dress with colored <note type="material">linen</note> suspenders) Something
            new is a combination of <note type="color">white</note> and colored <note type="material">linen</note> in a <note type="garment">suspender waist</note> that launders
            beautifully; $2.95 </p>
         <p>(illustration of a woman wearing a simple blouse with buttons, wearing a striped belt
            and plain skirt.) Particularly good in a simple <note type="garment">blouse</note> is the new heavy <note type="material">silk</note> called <note type="material">silk
            broadcloth</note>; in <note type="color">white</note> or <note type="color">flesh color</note>; $5.95 </p>
         <p>(illustration of a woman wearing a striped scarf with a fluffy hat.) <note type="color">Black</note> and <note type="color">white</note>
            striped <note type="material"><note type="material">velvet</note></note> line with brilliant <note type="color">green</note> velvet forms the <note type="garment">scarf</note> of a <note type="garment">skating set</note>; the
            <note type="garment">hat</note> is like the <note type="garment">scarf</note>, with a gay <note type="material">worsted</note> trimming; <note type="garment">hat</note>, $12; <note type="garment">scarf</note>, $15 </p>
         <p>SIMPLE <note type="material">crêpe de Chine</note> <note type="garment">negligées</note> of the type illustrated at the lower left make most
            acceptable Christmas gifts, because they are practical, as well as attractive; crêpe de
            Chine is the most serviceable of materials for this purpose.</p>
         <p>The model shown may be had in <note type="color">pink</note>, <note type="color">blue</note>, or <note type="color">white</note> <note type="material"><note type="material">crêpe de Chine</note></note>, or it may be had in
            other colors to order. The <note type="garment">fichu</note>, edged with a narrow <note type="material">knife plaiting</note> of the crêpe de
            Chine, is practically the only trimming. <note type="material">Knife plaiting</note> also appears at the Empire
            waist-line in both front and back.</p>
         <p>The model sketched in the middle at the bottom of the page is also of <note type="material">crêpe de Chine</note>.
            The front is softly box plaited, and the back shows two groups of box plaits at each
            side. Delicate <note type="material">lace</note> of a lovely pattern is used around the neck and to form the sleeves;
            the flowing coat of <note type="material"><note type="material">chiffon</note> cloth</note> has angel sleeves.</p>

         <p>A <note type="garment">CAP</note> AND A FLYAWAY <note type="garment">PETTICOAT</note></p>

         <p> With the <note type="garment">negligée</note> just described is a boudoir <note type="garment">cap</note> of <note type="material">chiffon</note><note type="material">cloth</note> and <note type="material">Binche <note type="material">lace</note></note>. The
            <note type="garment">cap</note> is made entirely by hand and is trimmed with a satin rosette at each side, which is
            the only decoration. It may be had in <note type="color">flesh color</note>, <note type="color">pink</note>, or <note type="color">blue</note> <note type="material"> chiffon cloth</note>.
            <note type="garment">Petticoats</note> are so much in demand that the model at the lower right would be most
            acceptable to the girl who is fond of fluffy things . The top is made of soft <note type="material">French
               taffeta</note>, and the flounce is of <note type="material">plaited chiffon</note>, with a ruching at the bottom. Bows and
            streamers of <note type="material">taffeta ribbon</note> trim the ruffle. The <note type="garment">petticoat</note> comes in <note type="colors">light colors</note>.</p>
         <p> The <note type="garment">underbodice</note> with the <note type="garment">petticoat</note> has been made to order to match the <note type="garment">skirt</note>. It is of
            <note type="material">ribbons</note> and plaited <note type="material">chiffon</note>. </p>

         <p>PICTURESQUE SETS</p>

         <p>The <note type="garment">two skating</note> sets illustrated on this page are most appropriate as Christmas gifts.
            The one at the upper left is of smart <note type="color">black</note> and <note type="color">white</note> checked <note type="material">velveteen</note> and <note type="color">red</note> <note type="material">chiffon</note>
            <note type="material">velvet</note>. The <note type="garment">skating sets</note> are exclusive designs of the shop which made them. </p>
         <p>The set sketched at the upper right is of a <note type="color">black</note> and <note type="color">white</note> striped <note type="materrial">velvet</note>, lined with a
            brilliant <note type="color">green</note> <note type="material">chiffon</note><note type="material">velvet</note>. The <note type="garment">hat</note> is of the same combination, with a <note type="material">fur</note> band and
            a gaily colored <note type="material">worsted</note> decoration of fruit. </p>
         <p> Very simple is the heavy <note type="material">silk</note> waist in the second sketch from the upper right. The
            material is the new <note type="material">silk</note> broad-cloth. <note type="color">White</note> <note type="material">silk</note> is used on the collar and cuffs.</p>
         <p>Second from the left is a <note type="garment">suspender waist</note> in <note type="color">pink</note> and <note type="color">white</note>, or <note type="color">blue</note> and <note type="color">white</note> <note type="matertial">linen</note>.
            Hem-stitching marks the division of the materials. The collar may be worn either open or
            closed. </p>
         <p>(Illustration of a woman wearing a <note type="color">pink</note>, <note type="color">blue</note>, or <note type="color">white</note> <note type="material">crêpe de chine</note> negligée.) A
            pretty as well as a practical Christmas gift is a <note type="material">crêpe de Chine</note> <note type="garment">negligée</note> with a
            surplice bodice frilled with narrow box plaitings; $11.75 </p>
         <p>(Illustration of a woman wearing princesse negligées.) The princesse lines are as
            popular is <note type="garment">negligées</note> as in formal garments is proved by this <note type="material">crêpe de Chine</note> model;
            <note type="garment">negligée</note>, $11.75; <note type="garmnet">cap</note>, $5 </p>
         <p>(Illustration of a woman wearing a fluffy petticoat with <note type="material">chiffon</note> and ribbon.) She who is
            fond of fluffy things will be charmed with a <note type="garment">petticoat</note> flounced with <note type="material">chiffon</note> and ribbon;
            <note type="garment">petticoat</note>, $9.75; <note type="garment">underblouse</note> to match. $9.25 </p>

         <p> Note. – Addresses of the shops will be furnished on request, or the Shopping Service of
            Vogue will buy for you without extra charge. Address Vogue Shopping Service, 443 Fourth
            Ave., New York City.</p>

         <p>Copyright Ⓒ 2012 Condé Nast</p>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
