<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>What She Wears</title>
            <author>Vogue Magezine</author>
            <editor> Tara McGee</editor>
         </titleStmt>

         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Penn State University, Digital Humanities</publisher>
            <date when="2025">2025</date>
            <availability status="free">
               <p>Distributed for educational and research use only.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <bibl>
               <title level="a">What She Wears</title>
               <author>Vogue Magazine</author>
               <pubPlace>New York</pubPlace>
               <publisher>Condé Nast</publisher>
               <date when="1915-12-01">December 1, 1925</date>
               <note>Transcribed from the December 1, 1925 issue of <title level="j">Vogue</title>,
                  Published by Condé Nast in New York.</note>
            </bibl>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text>
      <body>
         <p>94</p>
         <p> (Illustration of two women wearing long pleated skirts with hats.)</p>
         <p>(Left) In the <note type="color">black</note> <note type="material">velvet</note> <note type="garment">frock</note> with stiff <note type="color">gold</note> inserts, at the extreme left, the new
            kinetic silhouette gets its motion from a pleated circular front that swings free at the
            bottom. Beside it is a <note type="material">rep</note> <note type="garment">frock</note> with a long tie collar and an intricately cut skirt
            section that moves gracefully with the wearer </p>
         <p> (Illustration of two women wearing long <note type="garment">cape</note>s with <note type="material">fur</note> trim at neck, bottom, and
            cuffs.)</p>
         <p>(Right) <note type="garment">Cape</note>s or ingenious swaying panels at the back transform the static lines of last
            season into the animated silhouette of the moment. Both of these <note type="fur">fur</note>- trimmed <note type="material">velvet</note>
            <note type="garment">coat</note>s are plain at the front </p>
         <p>(Illustration of woman wearing <note type="material">chiffon</note> <note type="garment">dress</note> with flying sections)</p>
         <p> The fluttering sheerness of <note type="material">chiffon</note> lends itself especially well to loose hanging
            panels and flying sections of <note type="material">chiffon</note>s lends itself especially well to loose hanging
            panels and flying sections – a mode that calls for great skill and originality on the
            part of the designers </p>
         <p>(Illustration of a woman wearing a short <note type="color">cream</note> and <note type="color">gold</note> <note type="garment">dress</note>; smoking a cigarette.)</p>
         <p> This slim <note type="garment">gown</note> of <note type="color">cream</note> <note type="material">net</note> and <note type="color">brown</note> and <note type="color">gold</note> <note type="material">brocade</note>, slightly moulded to the figure,
            finds all its motion in the frothy fulness at the bottom of the shaped circular flounce </p>
         <p>(Illustration of a woman wearing a long <note type="garment">dress</note> with an uneven cut <note type="garment">dress</note> so that it
            flares.)</p>
         <p>For evening, a slightly moulded bodice is often seen above an uneven skirt so cut that
            it flares with graceful motion when the wearer walks or dances </p>














         <p>Copyright 2012 © Condé Nast</p>

         <p>December 1, 1925 95</p>

         <p>The Silhouette Moves!</p>
         <p>Sketches</p>
         <p>and</p>
         <p>Notes</p>
         <p>That Show the Modern Spirit of the Animated</p>
         <p>Fashion of the Flare</p>

         <p> (Left) The fulness and the pointed cut of the deep <note type="garment">cape</note> on this <note type="velvet">velvet</note> <note type="garment">wrap</note> give it its
            animation</p>

         <p>On these three models, the motion of the mode is obtained in three ways-by swinging
            jabots on the <note type="material">velveteen</note> <note type="garment">frock</note> at the left, by circular cut in the <note type="material">broadcloth</note> model in
            the middle, and by the wide semicircular front of the <note type="material">velours</note> <note type="garment">coat</note> at the right </p>

         <p>FLARES that spring from the front, the side, or the back, the circular swing of <note type="garment">coat</note>s,
            the sweep of new <note type="garment">cape</note>s, the flying lines of the jabot and the scarf, have all called
            into being a new mode--the mode of motion. The straight silhouette of past seasons was
            inert, static. The new, flared line is a living, moving, modern thing. The rough
            sketches on these two pages, showing clothes that smart women are wearing now,
            illustrate this theme of motion. The unfinished lines of these sketches, which have not
            as yet settled into repose, express the ever-shifting grace of the mobile silhouette.
            This is the impression presented by the new flaring fashions. Every step, every move
            displaces a godet, a pleat, a drapery, and sets astir a new dynamic rhythm.</p>
         <p>It has been a long time making its way-this mode of motion. This winter marks its first
            general acceptance. We clung for a long time to the straight, restricted line, because
            it gave us so little trouble. It was young. It was simple. It was smart because it was
            simple and young. And, as long as we kept to it tenaciously, we could not go very far
            wrong.</p>
         <p>But what has this new flared line to offer to offset the security of the old, familiar,
            tube-like silhouette? Vogue believes that it has a great deal to give in the furthering
            of a more progressive mode. Its first great advantage is its comfort. The straight line
            was made for standing still in a strenuous world keyed to motion. The flared line is
            designed for easy, unrestricted action. The new silhouette makes us less self-conscious
            about our clothes-walking, sitting, dancing-and more conscious of a new and exhilarating
            freedom and grace. Moreover, as long as the straight silhouette dominated clothes, the
            mode itself could not go forward. When two seams made a dress, what was left to
            encourage the invention of a Vionnet, who works with fabrics as a sculptor moulds his
            planes? What was left to stimulate the plastic skill of a Jean Patou, the kinetic, or
            made-for-motion, designs of a Lucien Lelong, the genius of all the designers to whom the
            making of clothes is an art expressive of its age?</p>
         <p> Within the new conception of the flare, there is no end to the variations that are
            possible. The precisely tailored <note type="material">tweed</note> <note type="garment">frock</note>, with its concealed pleats that flare only
            in motion, the <note type="material">chiffon</note> dress with its flying scarfs and floating panels, are both in the
            same modern spirit. But each meets in its own way the demands of its fabric and the
            needs of the occasion for which it is especially intended. Not only does the flared
            silhouette give a wider scope to the designer, but it offers more individuality to the
            woman who wears it. While the straight line was becoming to the great majority-to the
            average woman and the average figure-,it had little to give to the exception. The woman
            whose charm is her dignity comes into her own this year, because she chooses the type of
            flare that will emphasize that quality. On the other hand, the slight, young girl now
            wears the new moulded lines, clinging and then flaring, short and free, to accent every
            lithe line. She adopts the Greek grace of a Diana, not of a Minerva-and the new mode
            offers both. The tall woman chooses clothes that will tend to shorten the effect of
            length. Even a short woman finds the particular kind of flowing lines that will make her
            look less square. The skilful use of flares can be made to bring out one's good points
            and to minimize less fortunate ones.</p>
         <p>With the coming of the flare, we begin a new era of individuality-altogether modern, a
            little dangerous, and always interesting. There is no longer any single formula for
            chic. And just how the flare is to be adapted to its time and to its wearers is a story
            to be continued in many more issues of Vogue in the weeks to come.</p>

         <p>Copyright ©2012 Condé Nast</p>

      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
