<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" 
   type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" 
   type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>

<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Vogue Project: "What She Wears" Encoding</title>
            <author>Trinity Taylor</author>
         </titleStmt>

         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Excerpt from Vogue Magazine, “What She Wears” article.</p>
         </publicationStmt>

         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>USA</country>
                  <region>New York</region>
                  <repository>
                     <title>Vogue Archive</title>
                     <origDate when="1893-07-15">July 15, 1893</origDate>
                  </repository>
                  <idno>Vol. 2 Iss. 3</idno>
                  <msName>What She Wears</msName>
               </msIdentifier>
               <physDesc>
                  <typeDesc xml:id="sectionBorder">
                     <typeNote>Decorative border framing the “What She Wears” section
                        heading.</typeNote>
                  </typeDesc>
               </physDesc>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>

   <text>
      <body>
         <div1>
            <head>WHAT SHE WEARS</head>

            <div2>
               <p> I had an opportunity not long ago of seeing the complete trousseau, I was going
                  to say, but probably outfit would be a better word, of a very pretty married woman
                  who was going to <placeName>Newport</placeName>, on a visit to one of the most
                  “swagger” houses there. The lady I speak of is not very rich, and never employs an
                  expensive dressmaker, but she has a room fitted up as a workroom at the top of her
                  house, the only furniture of which is a deal table, big enough to serve as a
                  dining-board for eight or ten guests; a cheval glass and enormous cupboards on all
                  sides, to hold skirts, new materials and all that a dressmaker requires. Here she
                  employs two sewing women for six weeks in the spring and autumn, who, under her
                  direction—and she has a wonderful taste, almost a genius, indeed, for the
                  fashioning of outer garments—make all the lovely toilettes that she wears to balls
                  and dinners in the winter, and to <placeName>Newport</placeName> and
                     <placeName>Lenox</placeName> in the summer. It was her summer outfit that I
                  went to see, and for the first time I realized how very tasteful and becoming the
                  present fashions might become under skillful management. </p>

               <p> Of ball gowns she had only two, a primrose-colored <material>surah</material>,
                  which was not yellow or canary color, but just the soft pale tinge which belongs
                  to the primrose alone. The skirt was veiled with white lace flounces, each one
                  about three-eighths of a yard wide, and the low bodice was also covered with
                  billows of lace which were held in place by straps and bows of black velvet, of
                  which also the girdle was made. The other ball dress was of silver gray gros
                  grain, exquisitely embroidered in silk, with perpendicular vines of blue, brown,
                  and green, and the back breadth was of gray moiré, such as was worn in olden
                  times, made into a demi-train. The trimmings of the low corsage and the large
                  balloon sleeves were of sky blue silk velvet, and the bretelles of it passed over
                  each shoulder and were continued on each side of the skirt, thus making a finish
                  to the embroidered vines. It was a really lovely gown. </p>

               <p> Of afternoon costumes there was a great variety. I fell in love with one—made of
                     <material>Algerienne flounces</material>, covering to the waist a lilac silk
                  skirt. The high corsage was of delicate lilac silk, fairly hidden under delicious
                  chiffon ruffles with an embroidered edge—the sleeves were made of ruffle after
                  ruffle of chiffon, narrowing down to the wrist, and the girdle, instead of coming
                  down over the diaphragm as girdles have been doing of late, drew in at the
                  waist—and had three carved mother-of-pearl buckles—one in front and one under each
                  arm. The breakfast gowns were all cambrics and linens and all most picturesquely
                  and becomingly fashioned. There was a yachting costume of Galatea cloth, in a
                  delicate shade of blue, made with an Eton jacket to wear with a white silk shirt,
                  and there was a traveling dress in pale buff linen, very fetching indeed. </p>

               <p> The tea gown (that indispensable garment for house parties) was a marvelous
                  combination of white silk, acres of white lace, and soft apple-green trimmings.
                  Shoes and stockings to match every toilette were there, and the latter won my
                  particular admiration. Never did I see such dainty, flimsy fabrics of silk and
                  fine lace, the latter embroidered on the stockings and tapering to the ankle,
                  where they swelled toward the calf of the leg. They certainly were fearfully and
                  wonderfully made. </p>

               <p> And, by the way, English fashion papers tell us that the reign of white stockings
                  is beginning again in <placeName>England</placeName>. The old Queen always had a
                  mania for them and her well-colored hose first came to be generally worn; actually
                  prohibited them in Court circles. On one occasion a royal princess was dismissed
                  from the presence chamber because she wore a pair of black silk stockings with a
                  colored gown. The venerable lady was obliged to give in at last, however, and
                  colored stockings have been generally worn in the Queen’s household for several
                  years. Now, however, that white is so much in fashion, white stockings have
                  appeared again, which so pleases the Sovereign that she herself ordered
                  twenty-five pairs for the <persName>Princess May</persName>’s trousseau. Poor
                  Princess! Let us hope that she has small, dainty feet. </p>
            </div2>
         </div1>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
