<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Vogue Project Test Markup</title>
            <author>Molly Wright</author>
         </titleStmt>

         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Excerpt from Vogue Magazine, "What She Wears" article.</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <msDesc>
               <msIdentifier>
                  <country>USA</country>
                  <region>New York</region>
                  <repository>
                     <title>Vogue Archive</title>
                     <origDate when="1897-05-20">May 20, 1897</origDate>
                  </repository>
                  <idno>Vol. 9 Iss. 20</idno>
                  <msName>What She Wears: Need of a Spring Function...</msName>
               </msIdentifier>
               <physDesc>
                  <typeDesc xml:id="sectionBorder">
                     <typeNote>Geometric border around the heading for the What She Wears
                        article.</typeNote>
                  </typeDesc>
               </physDesc>
            </msDesc>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <!-- For a potential project implementation, I would also like to be able to notate the materials mentioned within the texts. -->
   <text>
      <body>
         <div1>
            <head hand="#sectionBorder">WHAT SHE WEARS</head>
            <div2>
               <head>NEED OF A SPRING FUNCTION - CHAMBRY GOWN - CORDED SILKS DISPLACING THE HEAVIER
                  QUALITIES - SOME "SNOB" COSTUMES WHICH ARE THE LATEST PARISIAN CREATIONS</head>
               <p> ALl the well-known town houses closed, the smart owners flown to the four points
                  of the compass, how dreary things begin to look for the residual not yet liberated
                  from the long-borne torments of a city in upheaval-a city where nothing is left
                  undone to make its householder's life, in- doors and out, as uncomfortable as
                  possible! Neither his doorway, nor his street approach, nor the air he breathes by
                  night or day within his domicile is on the one hand decent or on the other
                  healthful. Municipal tyranny and despotism render the tax-payer's life in this
                  metropolis anything but an enviable lot; nor may a tenant be looked upon other
                  than the helpless, miserable victim of street jobbery. At the first sign of mild
                  weather, could a part of the town population have followed their inclination, they
                  would have fled in thousands after their horrible winter's experience. As it is,
                  of a certainty not one will remain who has the chance of leaving. </p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>WANTED - A SPRING EQUIVALENT FOR THE HORSE SHOW</head>
               <p>One cannot but go on deploring the want of some great spring function which would
                  gather the smart world together and show off the season's new fashions. This
                  dulness has made it come to pass that demi-saison dressing is kept up until the
                  town is emptied of its fashionable contingent. Except such gowns as are worn at
                  private affairs which the public know nothing about, nothing smart in the way of
                  clothes is seen publicly at all. Unless strangers visited our watering places they
                  could get no idea of the choice creations women are wearing. That limit is
                  restricted to only a few favored localities where great fortunes flourish as the
                  green bay-tree.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>THE WEARING OF HAND-MADE LACE OBLIGA-TORY FOR THE WOMAN WHO WOULD BE
                  SMART</head>
               <p>The use of lace this summer is to be regal, and where the entire gown may not be
                  fashioned of it, for all the smart world are not million- aires, those who are not
                  will adorn themselves with yards of it for trimming, for very beautiful is real
                  lace in flouncing, and not to be despised. Chambry gowns trimmed with real lace
                  are dreams, for what is lovelier than that gauze or more suggestive of the Newport
                  season drawing so near? One lovely gown of this order now on its way to scenes of
                  conquest by and by you may call up before you in fancy, by starting with its white
                  satin slip to begin with, and notice the white chiffon and satin flounces on the
                  bottom in plissés. Over this falls one of white mousseline de soie, finished with
                  a plissé and over this again the dream-like white Chambry strewn with lilac 316
                  branches, untrimmed around the bottom, all three skirts separately hung, but
                  joined at the belt. The front is not gored, but drawn up straight across, caught
                  on the left hip and folded in a standing line towards the bottom. The space on the
                  left is filled in with a three flounce panel of solid lilac tissue, each flounce
                  incrusted with a barb of Venice point. These flounces are also sewed on a double
                  foundation of lilac tissue. This panel is then slipped under the slanting side of
                  the Chambry gauze and fastened back under the opposite gore seam, when it is
                  raised several inches higher than the front, producing distinct lines of grace and
                  preserving the harmony of the main skirt lines. A white silk bodice lining is
                  round, draped with white mousseline de soie, the back laid in the finest of
                  plaits, clasped by a wide belt of deep pansy satin, beautifully fitted in wide
                  bias folds. Over the upper front half of bodice is a double mousse- line de soie
                  chemisette boléro attached to col- lar band, fitting into the shoulders and laid
                  in wide box-plaits, one flounce shorter than the other and having at the bottom
                  the same Ven- ice barb incrustation. These flounces are shorter in the centre,
                  reaching only the top of the belt, which runs into an upper rounding point, and is
                  trimmed down the middle with several satin choux. White mousseline de soie
                  sleeves, shirred over the arm, with butterfly puffs above of Chambry gauze. Wrists
                  ex- quisitely incrusted with lace, and flaring collar band a mass of small
                  puckered mousseline de soie frills and upper plaitings of lace. For garden party,
                  Casino, dinner, dance or recep- tion it needs little imagination to picture the
                  success of blonde or brunette beauty wearing it.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head> THE OLD GROS-GRAIN AGAIN IN FAVOR</head>
               <p> Corded silks, the old gros-grains we were so fond of, have come in as the smart
                  silks for dressy affairs this summer, and being much lighter of texture than those
                  rich poult de soies are preferable. Youngish matrons are wearing these silks with
                  a very pretty style of bodice, having a picturesque element that would lend itself
                  admirably to a portrait. One such gown which is worthy of description has a
                  matchless color that might be a pale damask, rose or ruby tint. Its demi-traine
                  skirt has a narrow tablier of white satin, over which is laid a flat bit of
                  sixteenth-century altar lace of quaint design, and finished on the bottom by a
                  double plissé of cream-colored mousseline de soie; above it a band of match satin
                  ribbon in loops, starting from a flat bow in the centre. The bodice foundation is
                  a white silk lining, cut into a deep V back and front, with the gros-grain draped
                  over into a half-bodice, with a short flat basque to the hips only, where it is
                  very rounding and flares out quaintly, leav- ing the front in full cross drapery
                  of silk, fastening on the left side, but well toward the front, with four handsome
                  antique buttons brilliantly jeweled. The top of bodice has a cream-white satin
                  scarf drawn across the shoul- ders to form a short boléro, passing over the top of
                  under-bodice, then drawn up into a few plaits at the bust, where it is fastened by
                  two larger antique jeweled buttons, connected by a jeweled chain. The shoulders,
                  when fitted, show the neck to be half-low, and an inside mousseline de soie
                  chemisette, à la Vierge, is let in and drawn down into a V in front. A jeweled or
                  velvet collar must be worn, the neck being exposed for precisely that style of
                  ornamentation. Very short sleeves, merely a band to hold double mousseline de soie
                  plissés, with big black bows of that soft French satin ribbon now the rage for
                  hats and gowns. There are no ends, and the bows lie like epaulettes across the
                  shoulders.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>HOUSE COSTUME</head>
               <p>The new play called <mentioned><title type="play">Snob</title> by <persName>M.
                        Gustave</persName> Guiches</mentioned>, at the <placeName>Renaissance,
                     Paris</placeName>, brought out many deliciously new and pretty toilettes,
                     <persName>Mlle. Granier</persName> looking enchantingly lovely in four beauty
                  frocks, and <persName>Mlle. Mignard </persName> running As these gowns are her
                  very close on three. the newest creations from the best gown mak- ers in the
                  world, their description is of great importance. In the first act, <persName>Mlle.
                     Granier</persName> is seen wearing a charming house-dress, a re- ception gown
                  of figured mousseline de soie, of bluet ground, with a large bold design of
                  bluets, stems, leaves and branches overrunning the surface in an unrestrained
                  manner. A skirt of this design and character has no need of trimming, but hangs in
                  the grace of well arranged drapery, clasped in at the waist by long scarf to
                  match, with the ends fringed in steel beads. These scarfs, fringed with beads or
                  knotted fringe, are seen on many French gowns as the newest of smart touches. The
                  round bodice is drawn down into the waist by simple gathers, having an open front
                  with a straight vest in white satin, elaborately embroidered in steel, the edges
                  overlapping the gown fronts, and fine double bows of black and white pékiné ribbon
                  ornament the centre.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>TRAVELING GOWN</head>
               <p>In the second act <persName>Mlle. Granier</persName> wears a traveling gown in
                  gray cloth, walking length, skirt untrimmed. Its bodice is a long boléro, with
                  open fronts trimmed on each side length- ways, and spreading out into squares, low
                  at the sides with white passementerie. A pink- ish-red plastron of mousseline de
                  soie plissé, with collar band of the same over white silk. New model sleeves with
                  double bias epaulettes simply stitched.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>BALL GOWN</head>
               <p> In the third and last act, <persName type="title">Mlle. G.</persName>
                  wears a superb lace gown of marvelously beautiful white guipure, over cream white
                  satin, the front spangled with gold, including low bodice front as one with the
                  skirt. On the sides of the skirt branches of green and white orchids are posed
                  irregularly with the happiest effect. The low bodice of white satin is simply
                  draped with guipure, having a bertha of the same lace, falling from the
                  décolletage, and a spray of orchids on the left. Guipure sleeves from shoulder to
                  wrist fit the arm like a glove. A wide diamond and pearl collier round the neck of
                  the choicest and rarest gems.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>CREPE DE CHINE TEA GOWN </head>
               <p><persName>Mlle G</persName>- -also wears an exquisite tea-gown in rose pink crêpe
                  de chine, having a princesse back, and quantities of flowing skirt drapery. The
                  front is composed entirely of lace inser- tions, flowing down from a small open V
                  shaped neck as a pendant scarf, each side bordered by a lace jabot, with two short
                  ends crossing kerchief-wise at the neck, always so prettily effective. Beyond and
                  next the lace jabots come two crêpe de chine stoles from shoulder to hem graduated
                  in width, em- broidered in gold sequins in a V design with spaces between, and the
                  edges to match. Half-way up the skirt on the sides beyond these stoles two
                  flounces of lace are flatly laid VOGUE with space between-evidently to break the
                  sharp line of the stoles, as well as to elaborate the front symmetrically. There
                  are crêpe de chine sleeves of moderate top fulness, close- fitting to the arm,
                  with the wrists lace-trimmed on the opening of outside seam.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>WHITE HUSSAR JACKETS</head>
               <p> Very chic are little Hussar jackets in white cloth, for park, or road driving
                  later on in the summer by the sea. Boléros of white cloth braided and befrogged
                  are quite like eton waists, trim and becoming, and equally fit for driving.</p>
            </div2>
            <div2>
               <head>LIFE</head>
               <p>I saw many people, in gorgeous garments, sitting at tables gay with rich glass and
                  silver and gold. They were very merry, singing and laughing over their feasting.
                  But as I looked closer I saw that the dishes before them and the goblets which
                  they raised to their lips were all empty. And this is the story of life.</p>
            </div2>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>A simplistic ink illustration depicting a woman in a hat adorned with
                  flowers and a floral dress with flowing sleeves. </figDesc>
            </figure>
         </div1>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
